xmarks.com 2009-03-06

# Xmarks - Privacy Policy

Your privacy, and the privacy of all registered users of Xmarks.com, is important to us. Accordingly, we have adopted the following privacy policy. Our policy is based on the principles of notice, choice, access and security in the collection and use of all information regarding our users and their activities at our site. 

## Notice

This policy tells you, among other things, what information we gather from you how we may use or disclose that information and our efforts to protect it. Please read this policy carefully, and feel free to contact us at privacy@xmarks.com if you have any questions regarding its contents. We may change this policy at any time to correct technical or typographical errors, to increase your rights and protections or to comply with laws. If we change this policy in a way that reduces your rights or protections or adds new types of disclosures, we will provide notification before such changes would apply to information collected from or about you. 

### Types of Information Collected

In connection with your use of our site, we ask for and may collect a variety of information from and about you in different ways. For example, when you register to use our site, we ask for and store a username and email address. In addition, when you use Xmarks to synchronize your bookmarks with our server, we collect information such as the date and time of synchronization, your IP address, which version of our software you are using, and other information related to the transaction. As an intermediary in the synchronization process, we collect and store your bookmarks. We may also collect the information you disclose in any of our chat rooms, blogs, wiki pages, discussion groups, bulletin boards, and email you send to us. 

### Use of Cookies

Use of our site may require that you accept the use of cookies, which are small data files that our Web site sends to your browser for storage on your computer’s hard drive. We use cookies to protect confidential data, track activity at our site and better serve your needs and interests. 

### Use of Information

We use your personally identifying information to register you as a user of the site and to control access to your bookmarks. We may use your email address to contact you directly to alert of you of technical problems with your account, or, unless you opt out, to contact you regarding Xmarks services or products. (To opt out at any time, please log into your account.) We will never sell your email address to 3rd parties. We may also associate your personally identifying information with information we collect about your preferences and activities on the site, such as the particular pages you view at the site or other transactions you effect through the site in order to vary the content you receive in future visits to the site. 

Our discovery engine analyzes in aggregate the bookmarks of all users in order to deliver services of interest to other users. This aggregation and analysis process removes all personally-identifiable information from bookmarks. For example, if one thousand distinct users bookmarked nytimes.com and cnn.com in a folder called “news”, we would mark both of those sites as popular, similar, and related to the topic news. In doing so we would never provide any personally identifiable information linking those sites back to any of the thousand users that bookmarked them. We also exclude sites with a very small number of bookmarks from our algorithms; this means we don’t display any information on a site until a sufficient number of people have bookmarked it. 

Xmarks also displays site reviews, written by users, as part of our site information feature. These user-generated reviews do clearly identify the username of the author and provide a link to see a history of other reviews and site description edits made by that user. Contributing user-generated content on Xmarks is purely optional and is not a requirement to use our service. If you ever encounter content in an Xmarks review that you believe is offensive or in violation of a copyright, simply click the “Report This” link next to the review and we’ll investigate. 

By using the Xmarks browser add-on you give Xmarks permission to use bookmark information anonymously and in aggregate to power our discovery service. If after trying our product you do not want your bookmarks added to the collective wisdom of our bookmark corpus, you can easily uninstall the Xmarks browser add-on and delete your account by visiting Xmarks.com, logging in, and clicking My Account. 

### Disclosure of Information

We may disclose information to fulfill certain legal and regulatory requirements or if we believe, in good faith, that such disclosure is legally required or necessary to protect others’ rights or to prevent harm. 

## Choice

You may choose to delete your account at any time. Instructions on how to delete your account are available [here](http://wiki.xmarks.com/wiki/Foxmarks:_Frequently_Asked_Questions#How_do_I_delete_my_Foxmarks_account.3F). 

You may also choose to uninstall Xmarks from your computer at any time. Instructions on how to uninstall Xmarks are available [here](http://wiki.xmarks.com/wiki/Uninstalling_the_Extension). 

## Access

At any time after you have created an account on our site, you may [log in to your account](http://login.xmarks.com/account) to view and change information about your account. Once those changes are confirmed, any new item of information will replace the corresponding information previously provided. 

### Security

Please remember that you play a valuable part in security as well. Your password to access our site, which you select at registration, should never be shared with anyone and should be changed frequently. And, after you have finished using our site, you should log off and exit your browser so no unauthorized persons can use our site with your name and account information. Remember that any information you voluntarily disclose on-line in any news or message postings, discussion groups or chat rooms may be collected and used by others without your permission. Furthermore, if you provide any information to parties who operate Web sites that are linked to or from our site, different rules may apply to their collection, use or disclosure of your personal information. We encourage you to review these sites’ policies before revealing any sensitive or personal information. 

Regardless of the precautions taken by you or by us, "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet. We cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you transmit such information at your own risk. 

Effective Date: February 26, 2009.
